No
没有
so good evening good afternoon good
晚上好，下午好
morning depending on where you are I
早上取决于你在哪里
hope that our some folks from code one
希望我们的一些人从代码一开始
joining as they promised we are going
按照他们的承诺加入我们
now to have a ball for my Chicago e all
现在要为我的芝加哥所有人
hands they'll basically get some updates
他们基本上会得到一些更新
get some answered some questions
得到一些回答一些问题
answered by working group members and
由工作组成员回答
especially by Mike and Mike will first
特别是迈克（Mike）和迈克（Mike）首先
Bob with a few slides with his community
Bob和他的社区一起放了几张幻灯片
update talk about that answer a few
更新谈论那个答案一些
questions and then he has to run off but
问题，然后他必须逃跑，但是
everyone else still stay in the room and
其他所有人仍然呆在房间里
when we start with the official
当我们从官方开始
questions then we have five coupons for
问题，那么我们有五张优惠券
free ebook from Manning from my
我的曼宁提供的免费电子书
colleague Ken Finnegan about Java micro
同事Ken Finnegan关于Java micro
services and if you pose a good question
服务以及您提出的好问题
you can win one of these books except
您可以赢得其中一本书，但
for Wayne that's probably why he's
对于韦恩，这可能就是为什么他
running away
逃跑
so Mike take it over all right Thank You
所以迈克接管好了，谢谢
heiko so first of all I apologize that I
平子，首先我向我道歉
have to leave after 30 minutes however
必须在30分钟后离开
with Wayne and Tanya and Demetri and
与韦恩（Wayne）和塔妮（Tanya）以及德米特（Demetri）和
everybody in the room there's more than
房间里的每个人都比
enough people here who are deeply
这里有足够多的人
involved to answer any questions that
参与回答任何问题
I'm not around for us so so thank you
我不在我们身边，所以谢谢
for coming and we think that there's a
来了，我们认为有一个
lot of really cool stuff going on so
很多非常酷的事情正在发生
next slide please
请下一张幻灯片
so let's just start off with a quick
所以让我们开始快速
introduction to the the companies that
公司介绍
are involved in the strategic members on
参与战略成员
the left-hand side are the other ones
左边是其他人
that are doing the heavy lifting here so
在这里做繁重的工作
we are have a group of companies and
我们有一群公司，
people that from those companies and
这些公司的人
then office collected representatives
然后办公室召集代表
that are very active in the steering
在转向中非常活跃
committee the spec committee the
规范委员会
Marketing Committee and just generally
营销委员会和一般
doing an awful lot of work to get this
做很多工作来做到这一点
get this off the ground and so want to
把它拿出来，所以想
thank everybody and many of you were in
谢谢大家，你们中的许多人都在
the room actually put your just so put
房间实际上把你放了
your hand up if you're on one of the
如果您处于其中之一，请举起手来
committees involved in the working group
参与工作组的委员会
right so
对吧
yep so you can see you have a really
是的，所以你可以看到你有一个真正的
good cross-section of people that are
好的人的横截面
involved here and and so like I said
参与到这里等等，就像我说的
there they're certainly gonna be lots of
那里肯定会有很多
people here who can answer questions so
可以回答问题的人
just a very quick high-level roadmap of
只是一个非常快速的高层路线图
what's going on so we started this
发生了什么事，所以我们开始了
little adventure almost a year ago of
大约一年前的小冒险
course there's a big difference I mean
当然，我的意思是有很大的不同
everybody in this room has been around
这个房间里的每个人都在附近
the software industry for a long time
长期以来的软件行业
and you know there's a really big
而且你知道有一个很大的
difference between what gets announced
宣布之间的区别
and then the actual reality so the
然后是实际的现实
announcement you know a year ago was you
一年前你知道的公告是你
know we're moving Java EE to eclipse
知道我们正在将Java EE移到Eclipse
fill in the blanks later great so and
后来填补空白，很好，所以
we're gonna talk a little bit about so
我们将谈论一些
the scale of what that means but so so
这意味着什么的规模，但如此
but roughly what's going on at the
但大致上发生了什么
moment is and this is really happy to
现在是，这真的很高兴
say is we actually have a date for when
说我们实际上有个约会
we're gonna ship the first release of
我们将发布第一个版本的
the code that's being contributed into
被贡献到的代码
into Eclipse GlassFish so December 14th
12月14日进入Eclipse GlassFish
now the good news is that's a fairly
现在好消息是
real date as these things go because
这些事情发生的真实日期，因为
there's a plan and and it's it's you
有一个计划，是你
know it it's achievable but it's a
知道这是可以实现的，但这是一个
little bit on the aggressive side great
好斗的一面很棒
Demetrius it's not like it's a gimme
德米特里不是它是给我
right there's lots of stuff that that
对，有很多东西
has to get done but we're very hopeful
必须完成，但我们充满希望
that before the end of the year we are
在年底之前
going to be shipping a glassfish release
将要运送玻璃鱼
from eclipse and that's going to be the
从日食，这将是
culmination of and I call it a metric
高潮，我称之为度量
shit-ton of of work and then some point
工作的垃圾，然后是一点
but the really the the end goal here of
但真正的最终目标是
course is to create not a Java EE 8
当然是创建不是Java EE 8
release I should I should backtrack a
发布我应该回溯一个
little bit so we're gonna ship Eclipse
一点点，所以我们要运送Eclipse
GlassFish 5.1 and it's gonna be
GlassFish 5.1，它将成为
certified as Java EE eight compatible
认证为Java EE八兼容
but what this really is about is
但这实际上是关于
establishing Jakarta is its own spec
建立雅加达是它自己的规范
process and we still have some work to
流程，我们还有一些工作要做
do on that and we'll talk a little bit
做到这一点，我们会谈一点
about it as we go through so some recent
关于它，因为我们经历了一些最近
accomplishments so just to kind of give
成就只是为了付出
you a scale for what we're talking about
你是我们正在谈论的尺度
here is you know since basically January
这是从一月份开始就知道的
1 which is when we really kind of got
1那是当我们真的得到
this thing going at the consolidation
这件事在巩固
we've on-boarded 39 new
我们已经推出了39个新产品
Jex and there's been a few talks I know
杰克斯（Jex），我知道有一些谈话
where they've talked about the scale of
他们谈到规模的地方
this but between the T CK's and the in
这个，但在T CK和
the glass efficient implementations and
玻璃的高效实现和
the jar files and everything word
jar文件和所有单词
it's like tenth roughly ten million
大概是十分之一
lines of code right and that's excluding
正确的代码行，但不包括
comments right like thirteen and a half
大约十三点半的评论
million lines that's including comments
百万行，其中包括评论
though yeah so but anyway so can we all
虽然是的，但无论如何我们都能
agree that's a lot of code all right
同意很多代码都可以
let's move on hundred and so we've
让我们继续前进，所以我们已经
on-boarded 160 new committers and the IP
加入了160位新提交者和IP
team the watches everything that's
配合手表的一切
coming into Eclipse projects is you know
进入Eclipse项目是您知道的吗
already done more you know thirty
已经做了更多，你知道三十
percent more work year-to-date than they
年初至今的工作量比他们多百分之
did all of last year
去年全部
and I want to by the way you know thank
我想顺便说一句谢谢
the Oracle team that we're working with
与我们合作的Oracle团队
and I guess future you're the only one
我想未来你是唯一的一个
here from the Oracle team today but
今天来自Oracle团队，但是
they've been great to work with the weed
他们与杂草合作很棒
the this the steering committee is
这个指导委员会是
chaired by will Lyons and he's been
由Will Lyons担任主席，他一直
absolutely amazing it's been a very
绝对惊人，这是一个非常
constructive and you know very congenial
建设性的，你知道很投机
collegial process all the way through so
整个过程一直如此
I mean there's been and you know the
我的意思是曾经有过，你知道
thing about it is from the Oracle side I
关于它的事情是从甲骨文方面我
mean they're taking all this code that
表示他们正在采用所有这些代码
works perfectly well right where it is
正确的工作原理
and we're dragging them through the
我们将它们拖到
Eclipse process and it's an awful lot of
Eclipse过程，其中有很多
work on their side to basically get them
在他们一边工作，基本上可以让他们
back to where they were when they
回到他们当时所在的地方
started so it is it is an enormous
开始，所以这是一个巨大的
amount of work and then on our side the
大量的工作，然后在我们这边
the pain that we have to bear is dealing
我们必须承受的痛苦
with the Oracle lawyers so negotiating
与甲骨文律师进行谈判
that the TCK agreement is was an
TCK协议是
enormous amount of fun and and by fun
大量的乐趣和乐趣
it's like kind of like catching leprosy
有点像麻风病
but and then we you know have this
但是然后我们你知道有这个
approved plan and we've keep going and
批准的计划，我们将继续前进，
this is where we are now in terms of the
这就是我们现在所处的位置
onboarding so basically we've gotten
因此，基本上我们已经
pretty much every single one of these
这些几乎每一个
projects to the point where the next the
投影到下一个
next thing for them to do is to ship a
他们要做的下一件事是运送一个
release from eclipse and exit incubation
从日食中释放并退出孵化
and action
和行动
become you know full fledged projects
成为你知道成熟的项目
that eclipse and you know trust me
日食，你知道相信我
that's like it's an enormous amount of
就像是
work to get us to this point so some
努力使我们达到这一点，所以一些
other things that's done and I think
其他事情已经完成，我认为
this is one of the main reasons why we
这是我们为什么要这么做的主要原因之一
wanted to have this Town Hall is we have
想拥有这个市政厅
this draft spec process that's open for
该规范草案流程可供
community review and I should have
社区审查，我应该有
probably put a link in there somewhere
可能在某处放置了链接
but if you if you have any questions you
但是如果您有任何疑问，
know feel free to drop Wayne or I a line
知道随时放下韦恩或我一行
or but we want the community to give us
或者，但我们希望社区给我们
feedback because this new spec process
反馈，因为此新规范流程
is gonna be absolutely critical to the
对
future success of this entire initiative
整个计划的未来成功
because really what were what this is
因为这到底是什么
all about is increasing the pace of
一切都在加快步伐
innovation in this area so that we can
在这一领域的创新，使我们能够
have um you know more more
你知道更多吗
community-based specifications to evolve
基于社区的规范不断发展
the Jakarta platform going forward then
雅加达平台将继续发展
there's a whole bunch of other stuff
还有很多其他的东西
that has to get done this kind of
必须完成这种
process-oriented
面向过程
and we're going to talk a little bit
我们要谈一点
about the IP flows later and and but
有关IP流的信息
this is an indeed this is an enormous
这确实是一个巨大的
amount of work on sort of our side as
我们这边的工作量
well in terms of drafting new licenses
在起草新许可证方面做得很好
and making sure that you know every I is
并确保你知道我每个人
dotted and every T is crossed in terms
点缀，每个T都用术语交叉
of the IP flows so that when we create
IP流量，因此当我们创建
specifications at the Eclipse Foundation
Eclipse Foundation中的规范
and the Jakarta working group that they
和雅加达工作组
are IP clean and the whole industry can
是IP清洁的，整个行业可以
base their products but more importantly
建立产品基础，但更重要的是
their applications on top of this new
他们在这个新产品上的应用
platform feeling very secure about that
平台对此感到非常安全
um so yeah just flip through that so in
嗯，是的，只是翻阅
terms of the spec process so when you're
规范流程的条款，因此当您
reading this document a couple of things
阅读这份文件的几件事
just to keep in the screen just went
只是为了保留在屏幕上
blank up here
在这里空白
I didn't do anything modest mode folks
我没有做谦虚的人
do see us
确实看到我们
daro much better everybody loves max so
darío好多了，每个人都爱max，所以
some of the guiding principles code
一些指导原则代码
first so this is one that's near and
首先，这是附近的一个
near and dear to my heart and this is
亲爱的亲爱的，这是
the idea that the best way to innovate
最好的创新方式的想法
is to try things out first and in
是先尝试然后再尝试
particular try things out in open source
特别尝试开源的东西
and in and then so really what we want
然后我们真正想要的是
to do is get to a point where before you
要做的就是到达你之前
bring a before you decide that you want
在您决定要带一个之前
to make us new spec you have to hit two
要使我们成为新规格，您必须打两点
criteria one is you have to demonstrate
标准之一是你必须证明
that you can actually build it right
你实际上可以正确地构建它
that you can build running code that
您可以构建运行代码
does X whatever that is and and so in
X是什么，等等
the second because we all seen
第二，因为我们都看到了
specifications which were designed in a
在一个
room that you know theoretically could
您理论上可以知道的房间
be implemented but why would you ever do
被实施，但是你为什么会做
it that way and you know there's all
这样，你知道所有的一切
kinds of examples from that right in
右边的各种例子
Java EE and that's the first criteria
Java EE，这是首要条件
the second criteria is that somebody
第二个标准是有人
cares right we've also seen also code
在乎，我们也看到了代码
and specs for that matter where people
和规格，这件事在哪里人
do things and nobody actually cares so
做事情，实际上没人在乎
what we want to get to is the idea where
我们要去的想法是
we're doing this right now with with the
我们现在正在使用
J no sequel project where they've got
他们没有的J续集项目
working code they've demonstrated that
他们已经证明的工作代码
people actually do we're willing to use
人们实际上会愿意使用
it now it's time to actually start doing
现在是时候开始真正地做
a spec and I don't really think that's
规格，我真的不认为那是
it that those two criteria are important
这两个标准很重要
you know you can build it and that
你知道你可以建造它
people care no more spec lead
人们不再关心任何规格线索
so the JCP process for those that know
因此，对于那些知道
it well knows that there's the way that
众所周知，有办法
the process works is that there's a each
该过程的工作原理是，每个
spec has a spec lead which is a company
spec有一家公司的规范负责人
and 99 times out of 100 that company is
在100的公司中，有99次是
Oracle and all the contributions go to
Oracle和所有贡献都投入
the spec lead and then spec need license
规范负责人，然后是规范需要许可证
the spec out to the world and so the way
规格向全世界发布
that this is gonna work at Eclipse is
这将在Eclipse中起作用
contributions are licensed from the
捐款由
contributor to the consumers directly
直接为消费者做出贡献
and the coop foundation itself doesn't
合作社基金会本身并没有
acquire any IP rights and there's no
获得任何知识产权，没有
special
特别
for any particular company so it's a
对于任何特定的公司，这是一个
much more vendor-neutral approach we're
我们采用的是与供应商无关的方法
gonna run the specs as open-source
将以开源形式运行规范
projects so basically the if you read
所以基本上，如果你读
the spec process what you'll see is that
规范过程中您将看到的是
it's basically like a specialization of
基本上就像是
the Eclipse development process so we've
Eclipse开发过程，所以我们已经
had this development process that
有这个发展过程
Eclipse it's that's you know performed
Eclipse就是您知道执行的
well as an open-source community process
以及开源社区流程
for many many years let's just basically
多年以来，我们基本上
add the little bit that we need to to
添加我们需要的一点
make it apply for specs the JCP had this
使其适用于JCP的规格
notion of reference implementations
参考实现的概念
which is a perfectly fine idea and what
这是一个非常好的主意，还有什么
the reference limitations were normative
参考限制是规范性的
what that means is if this if the spec
这意味着如果规范
was ambiguous if the gck didn't test
如果gck没有测试，那就太含糊了
something then you tried then the
然后你尝试了一些
reference implementation told you how
参考实施告诉您如何
you were supposed to do something and so
你应该做点什么，所以
instead of that approach this process is
而不是那种方法，这个过程是
gonna have the notion of compatible
会有兼容的概念
implementations and there must be at
实现，必须有
least one under an open-source license
至少有一个开源许可证下的
before you can declare the spec final
在您声明规格最终之前
but it's not that there's a special
但这并不是说有特殊之处
reference implementation that is
参考实现
normative so that's that's actually
规范的，那就是实际上
quite different the process of
完全不同的过程
certification and is going to be self
认证，并将成为自我
self certification but don't forget the
自我认证，但不要忘记
tcks are going to be open source and all
tcks将是开源的，所有
of your your certification results are
您的认证结果是
going to be published publicly so it's
将要公开发布，所以
gonna be a very different certification
将会是一个完全不同的认证
process than TCK process than what we've
流程比TCK流程比我们的流程
had with Java EE 8 the Java EE in the
使用Java EE 8的Java EE
past and in particular up until very
过去，尤其是直到
recently the tcks were not only closed
最近tcks不仅关闭了
source they were a proprietary and
来源，他们是专有的
highly confidential right if you wanted
高度保密的权利，如果你想
to get the Java EE TCK a license to the
获得Java EE TCK的许可证
Java EE tcks
Java EE问题
you had to sign a nondisclosure with
您必须与签署保密协议
Oracle just to get a copy of the
Oracle只是为了获得一份副本
contract right I mean like that's how
合同权利，我的意思是那样
confidential this stuff was and so we're
机密的东西是，所以我们
gonna go from one very extreme position
要从一个非常极端的位置出发
to here it is and I think there's gonna
到这里，我想
be a very different dynamic once
曾经是完全不同的动力
now that the TC keys are open-source
现在TC键是开源的
because if somebody thinks the test is
因为如果有人认为测试是
bogus you can have a conversation about
假的你可以谈谈
that in a public forum which is a very
在一个公共论坛上，
very different dynamic than the way it's
动态与它的方式截然不同
happened in the past and then you know
发生在过去，然后你知道
if you if you're compatible you can get
如果您兼容，就可以得到
the brand are you through a trademark
品牌是您通过商标获得的
license and by the way you will have to
许可证，而且您将必须
be a member of the Eclipse Foundation
成为Eclipse Foundation的成员
there's no licensing bees there's no
没有授权蜜蜂，没有
royalties but you do have to be a member
特许权使用费，但您必须成为会员
and so a little bit on the background on
在背景上有一点
the IP flows is that we have to change
IP流是我们必须改变
what I mentioned earlier that we have to
我之前提到的，我们必须
change a whole bunch of documents or
更改一堆文件或
write a whole bunch of documents so what
写一大堆文件
are we changing and why are we changing
我们在改变，我们为什么在改变
them and why is this important for
他们，为什么这很重要
people that are involved in eclipse so
参与日食的人
the idea is Eclipse has always had this
这个想法是Eclipse一直都有
symmetrical inbound light without bound
对称无界入站光
licensing model that's the way we've
许可模式就是我们的方式
always worked and the default license is
始终有效，默认许可证为
the EPL which is actually a copyleft
EPL实际上是一个copyleft
license next slide so the problem
许可下一张幻灯片，这样的问题
statement is we want to have a spec
声明是我们想要一个规格
process we wanted you code first so we
流程，我们希望您先编码，所以我们
want to be able to allow people to build
希望能够允许人们建造
stuff in EPL license projects it gets a
EPL许可项目中的内容
little bit easier if it's Apache or BSD
如果是Apache或BSD，会容易一些
license but we have to also support our
许可证，但我们还必须支持我们的
own license and some lawyers I mean I
我自己的执照和一些律师
don't know how much time you've spent
不知道你花了多少时间
with lawyers but basically they're
与律师，但基本上他们是
perfect the lawyers get paid a lot of
完善律师获得的报酬很多
money to think about everything that
钱去思考一切
could possibly ever go wrong right
可能永远会出错
that's what lawyers do that's why
那就是律师所做的，这就是为什么
there's so much fun at parties and so
派对上有很多乐趣，所以
there's so some lawyers had reservations
所以有些律师有所保留
about if we take code from an EPL
关于我们是否从EPL中获取代码
license and it's copyleft can we
许可证，它是copyleft我们可以
actually put that into a spec so what
实际上将其放入规格中
we're going to be doing is we're going
我们要做的就是我们要
to be updating the eclipse contributor
更新日食贡献者
agreements the committer agreements are
提交者协议是
Terms of Use to basically say hey if you
使用条款基本上是说嘿
contribute code to eclipse and we decide
将代码贡献给日食，我们决定
to put that in a spec you're okay with
把它放在你还可以的规格中
that now we don't think this is
现在我们不认为这是
controversial at all if you're
如果你有争议的话
contributing code to an open community
向开放社区贡献代码
the idea that somebody might want to you
有人可能想要你的想法
know write a spec from that should not
知道写一个规范不应该
be we don't think that should be a
是因为我们不认为这应该是
controversial statement and that last
有争议的声明，最后
bullet I probably should have deleted
我可能应该删除的项目符号
for this for this point but we also have
对于这一点，但我们也有
to update these agreements anyways to
无论如何将这些协议更新为
get some GP so that's that's the update
得到一些GP，那就是更新
that I have
我有
throw it open to questions at this point
在这一点上提出问题
thank you I have a question about the
谢谢，我对
TCK I've read that the TCK eats from is
TCK我读过TCK吃的是
a kind of monolith not split according
一种不按
the different specifications so is it
不同的规格是这样
still the case is there a plan to change
仍然有改变计划的情况
that so is it still a case yes
那还是这样吗
the TCK was contributed by Oracle and it
TCK由Oracle贡献，
is a monolith not only it's even worse
是一个整体，不仅更糟
than that actually because not only is
比这实际上是因为
it a monolith the testing harness that
它是一个完整的测试工具
it runs in predates Jack j-unit 1.0
它在杰克j-unit 1.0之前运行
great so it's not only is it a model if
很棒，所以它不仅是一个模型，如果
the framework the testing framework
框架测试框架
itself is you know really old like
本身就是你知道真的很老
almost as old as that I am so so so yes
几乎和我一样大，所以是
that's the current state is there a plan
这是当前状态，是否有计划
to break it up no is there a desire to
分解它没有欲望
break it up yes and this is a perfect
分解它，这是一个完美的选择
example of where the community can get
社区可以得到的例子
involved right that's to be successful
涉及成功的权利
we we do believe that they do we need to
我们确实相信他们确实需要
have T sit like a TCK per project kind
每个项目类型都像TCK一样坐着
of map and and in my rich fantasy life
和我丰富的幻想生活中
we actually use a modern test harness
我们实际上使用了现代化的测试装置
and move the test to something new both
并将测试移至新的东西
of those by themselves are enormous jobs
这些本身就是巨大的工作
and we are going to need help from
我们将需要以下方面的帮助
everybody to make that possible right
每个人都做到这一点
does that make I mean we definitely need
这是否意味着我确实需要
help but there's I don't think there's
帮助，但有我不认为有
anybody that disagrees with those goals
任何不同意那些目标的人
yes thank you
是的，谢谢
more questions and let me start one okay
还有更多问题，让我开始吧
okay yes Oh the old Java EE
好的，是的，旧的Java EE
specification had some promising they do
规范有一些希望
to be backward compatible we haven't
向后兼容我们还没有
talked anything about that and I also
谈到了任何事情，我也
find that there was there was good but
发现那里很好，但是
it was also bad things without that
没有那也是坏事
hindered innovation in the indication so
因此阻碍了适应症的创新
what's your thought about backward so
你对落后有什么想法
the first point is that's not my
第一点是那不是我的
decision I am not the boss of you or
决定我不是你的老板
anybody else so the role of the Eclipse
其他人，所以Eclipse的作用
Foundation do you have to remember the
基础你要记住
coo foundation is not a vendor right our
COO基金会不是我们的供应商
job here is not to tell people what to
这里的工作不是要告诉人们
do so that's going to be a decision of
这样做将是
the spec committee and and the you know
规格委员会，您知道
however we decide to basically guide the
但是我们决定从根本上指导
architecture going forward you know my
未来的建筑，你知道我的
personal opinion is that you know being
个人观点是你知道
backwards compatible forever is not a
永远向后兼容不是
great idea for any technology and this
任何技术的好主意
technology is starting to approach
技术开始出现
twenty years in the of age and so
大约二十岁
starting to actually you know you know
开始实际上你知道你知道
there is a deprecation process there has
有一个过时的过程
been in the past it just didn't get used
过去，只是没有被使用
a lot and so I think that there's a an
很多，所以我认为有一个
opportunity to actually make use of the
实际利用的机会
deprecation policies that were there the
当时的折旧政策
the culture at the Eclipse Foundation
Eclipse基金会的文化
itself and you look at the Eclipse IDE
本身，然后看一下Eclipse IDE
right we take even though we didn't have
是的，即使我们没有
a formal spec process at eclipse we take
eclipse的正式规范流程
backwards compatibility very seriously
向后兼容非常认真
right you can still run plug-ins on the
对，您仍然可以在
Eclipse IDE they were written you know
他们写的Eclipse IDE
quite a few years ago so it's it's not
相当多年前，不是
we don't you know we don't want to sort
我们不知道我们不想排序
of open the floodgates to you know
你知道打开水闸
anybody can change anything and
任何人都可以改变任何东西，
completely break backwards compatibility
完全打破向后兼容性
but there has to be some kind of
但必须有某种
give-and-take but actually you know
付出但实际上你知道
folks like Demetri and Kevin Moore
像Demetri和Kevin Moore这样的人
probably have more to say about this
可能还有更多话要说
than I do what you some time ago themes
比我前些时候做的主题
he came out of a technical vision for
他的技术远见卓识
the things you have mentioned in our
您在我们的文章中提到的内容
covers there so we would like to embrace
涵盖那里，所以我们想拥抱
innovations right and keep backwards but
创新正确并保持落后，但
we also would like to remove some older
我们也想删除一些旧的
stuff which is actually not needed so
实际上不需要的东西，所以
don't worry about papers compatibility I
不用担心论文的兼容性我
think it is all about backwards
认为这全是倒退
compatibility and I hope that Jakarta is
兼容性，我希望雅加达是
going to be the same but rigidity wants
会是一样的，但刚性要
to do little bit of cleanup right and
做一点清理吧，
remove some unnecessary parts
删除一些不必要的部分
unnecessary the key working right and
不必要的关键工作权利和
there's also there's a I think there's
还有一个我认为有
another possibility too which is around
还有另一种可能性
maybe creating not a huge number but
也许创造的不是一个巨大的数字，但
maybe a few more profiles the admit that
也许更多的个人资料承认
you know match you know modern
你知道比赛，你知道现代
application requirements a little bit
应用需求
better
更好
they there's sort of a in the
他们在里面
conversations that I've been in on the
我一直在讨论的话题
spec committee and there's definitely a
规范委员会，肯定有一个
lot nobody wants to have a whole bunch
很多人都不想拥有一大堆
of them but I mean there could be there
他们，但我的意思是可能在那里
could be a you know one or two more so
可能是一个，你知道一两个
that's another way to evolve it right as
这是发展它的另一种方式
you defined some profiles that leave
您定义了一些离开的配置文件
some baggage behind and but and because
后面有一些行李，但是因为
they're new they don't have the same
他们是新的，他们没有相同的
list of backwards requirements as as the
向后需求列表，如
full platform as you mentioned profiles
您提到的完整平台资料
there is another eclipse project called
还有另一个名为Eclipse的项目
micro profile what's it take on that
微观概况这是怎么回事
with respect to cut to toccata and the
关于削减toccata和
future of Jakarta
雅加达的未来
so you asking my personal opinion or I
所以你问我个人的意见还是我
mean you can mark that as personal so so
意味着您可以将其标记为个人，这样
what I mean the first thing to say is
我要说的第一件事是
Eclipse micro profile is a open source
Eclipse微型概要文件是开源的
project at Eclipse that that published
在Eclipse上发布的项目
some specifications and that community
一些规范和那个社区
and that project will make their own
该项目将使自己的
decisions right it's not their you know
正确的决定不是他们知道的
my job is not to go and boss people
我的工作是不去老板人
around
周围
right so there
对，在那里
yes that said in in my I think that
是的，我认为
micro profile was originally created
微型个人资料最初是创建的
because the pace of innovation in Java
因为Java的创新步伐
EE wasn't keeping up that was the
EE没有跟上那是
original raison d'tre for micro profile
原始的raison d'être微外形
we now have a position in a situation
我们现在在某种情况下有一个位置
where it's been around for a year and a
在那里已经一年多了
half at a little bit more it's gotten
一半多一点
quite successful you know project Khaled
非常成功，您知道项目Khaled
on from Oracle is now using it so it's
从Oracle开始使用它，因此
it's God it's not even the original
是上帝，甚至不是原始的
founding members it's got you know
创始成员知道了
pretty demonstrable ly broad industry
相当可观的行业
support so I think over time once the
支持，所以我认为随着时间的流逝
Jakarta e spec process is up and running
Jakarta e spec流程已启动并正在运行
and has been demonstrated to work that
并被证明可以工作
it would make a lot of sense for micro
对于微观来说这很有意义
profile to become part of it okay thank
个人资料成为它的一部分好吗谢谢
you but it's it's that needs to happen
你，但这就是需要发生的事情
in a prior it at a pace that feels right
事先感觉良好
for all the parties involved yeah
对于所有参与的各方
another question on the principle the
关于原理的另一个问题
guiding principles you said no more
您不再说的指导原则
speculate I know where it comes from
推测我知道它来自哪里
with the IP flow but you still probably
与IP流，但你仍然可能
want someone in a project that does the
希望有人参与一个项目
work that calls for a meeting that
要求召开会议的工作
writes the meeting notes that write the
写会议笔记，写
document and these things yep still
文件，这些东西仍然
exists
存在
well there's you had any rate up toward
好吧，你有什么机会
I agreed with everything except except
我同意一切，除了
the write the document so so the first
这样写文件，所以第一个
thing okay so yes Eclipse projects have
没关系，所以Eclipse项目有
project leaders so specification
项目负责人，所以规格
projects under Jakarta or at the
在雅加达或在
consolidation will have project leaders
合并将有项目负责人
but the position of an eclipse project
但是日蚀项目的位置
leader is a position of responsibility
领导者是负责任的职位
not a position of authority so a project
不是授权职位，而是项目
leader at eclipse is responsible for
eclipse的负责人负责
making sure that the project is
确保该项目是
operating properly and following the
运行正常并遵循
open source rules of engagement and so
开源参与规则等
on
上
but it's it's they don't you know
只是因为他们不知道
they're not the boss and in particular
他们不是老板，特别是
one of the things that I think I hope is
我想我希望的一件事是
a change is there are examples in the
变化是有例子
past at JCP specifications where there
过去在JCP规范那里
was a jsr that was there there was an
是一个jsr，那里有一个
expert group that was there and there
在那里的专家组
would be remarkably little conversation
很少交谈
for a long period of time and in the
在很长一段时间内
spec lead would show up with a document
规范负责人将显示一个文档
and say there's the spec we're gonna
并说有我们要的规格
have the vote in two weeks maybe
两周后可以投票
slightly exaggerating to make my point
有点夸张以表达我的观点
but that's not what I would call an open
但这不是我所说的公开赛
and collaborative process so in in the
和协作过程
equip specification process the
装备规范过程
expectation is that it's a group of
期望它是一群
people working together and everyone is
人们一起工作，每个人都是
a committer and if you have it and the
一个提交者，如果有的话，
way that it works at eclipse is if
它在日食的工作方式是
you're you know if you're collaborating
你知道你是否在合作
on a document every single committer on
在文档上的每个提交者
that project is going to have edit
该项目将要进行编辑
access to the document now the
现在访问文档
interesting thing about that is of
有趣的是
course if you think about it what does
当然，如果你考虑一下
that mean well one thing it means is
这意味着一件事意味着
you're gonna have more conflict but the
你会有更多的冲突，但是
conflict is gonna be open it's gonna be
冲突将会公开
discussed and ultimately there's gonna
讨论，最终将
have to be perhaps some arbitration but
必须进行一些仲裁，但是
it's not going to be it's gonna be a
它不会是它将成为一个
much more collaborative process than
协作过程比
what we had at the JCP and that's got
我们在JCP拥有的东西
some good things about it and perhaps
关于它的一些好东西，也许
some bad things about it but that's
一些不好的事情，但这就是
definitely the way we want to go yeah my
绝对是我们想要的方式，是的，我的
voting was riding was a bit bad but
投票虽然有点糟糕，但是
about like getting ahead dragging the
关于像继续拖动
crowd along sure done pretty much
人群肯定做得很好
everybody in this room has been a leader
这个房间里的每个人都是领导者
in some way in an open-source project
以某种方式在开源项目中
and you so you know the the metaphor
而且你知道隐喻
about herding cats right we've all heard
关于放牧猫，我们都听说过
it we've all lived it right it's that's
我们所有人都过着正确的生活，那就是
I think the way it's it's going to be
我认为它将是这样
though
虽然
[Music]
[音乐]